(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T09:00:41.640164",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
5周年記念 ＆ 新衣装お披露目ライブ
5th Anniversary Live & New Costume Unveiling
歌を歌う意味を
What is the meaning of singing songs?
生き続けていく意味を
What is the meaning of continuing to live?
考えても答えなんてないと知ってる
I know there's no answer even if I think about it.
白も黒も世界から消えた
White and black vanished from the world,
そこに何が残るのだろうか
what will remain there?
いなくなったら忘れてしまうか
If I disappear, will I be forgotten?
違う 違う 軌跡がここにあるよ
No, no, the miracle is right here.
たった一人の君と出会えて
Meeting you, who are one and only,
私は今を生きてるの
I am living in the present.
これから起こるすべてのことを
All the things that will happen from now on,
一緒に見よう
let's see them together.
最初から最後までだよ
From the very beginning to the end.
今日はAZKiの年越しライブに来てくれてありがとう！開拓者のみんなと一緒に歌ってね！
Thank you for coming to AZKi's New Year's Eve live! Let's sing together, everyone!
歌を歌う意味を
What is the meaning of singing songs?
生き続けていく意味を
What is the meaning of continuing to live?
一歩一歩確かめるように見つけよう
Let's find it by confirming step by step.
ときに暗く冷たい世界で
In a world that is sometimes dark and cold,
弱く脆く崩れそうになる
it becomes weak, fragile, and ready to collapse.
いなくなったら忘れてしまうか
If I disappear, will I be forgotten?
違う 違う 君の声が聴こえたんだ
No, no, I heard your voice.
たった一人の君と出会えて
Meeting you, who are one and only,
私は今を生きてるの
I am living in the present.
これから起こるすべてのことを
All the things that will happen from now on,
一緒に綴ろう
let's chronicle them together.
最初から最後までだよ
From the very beginning to the end.
この世界を
This world...
大好きでいたいよ
I want to keep loving it.
ずっと...
Forever...
時計の針が零時を指した
The clock's hands pointed to midnight.
気が遠くなるような時間が過ぎた
An eternity of time passed by.
世界は変わる そこに君はいない
The world changes, but you are not there.
それでも良いと思えたんだよ
Yet I felt that was still alright.
たった一人の君と出会って
Meeting you, my one and only,
（かけがえのない開拓者よ）
(my irreplaceable pioneer,)
私は今を生きてるの
I am living in the present now.
（私たちのストーリーを）
(Our story,)
今まで起きたすべてのことを覚えていてね
Please remember everything that has happened until now.
最初から最後までだよ
From the very beginning to the very end.
ここがスタート
This is the start.
ここがスタート ah
This is the start, ah.
歌を歌う意味を
The meaning of singing songs,
生き続けていく意味を
the meaning of continuing to live,
今やっとね 見つけたような気がしたよ
I feel like I've finally found them now.
皆さん、こんアズキ！
Everyone, Hello AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲッサ―ということで！
Mic in right hand, map in left, getting a zero-guess on your heart!
皆さん、AZKi 5周年ライブ With U、みんなと一緒にこれからもお越しいただきありがとうございます！わあー！
Thank you all so much for coming to AZKi's 5th Anniversary Live "With U" and being with us today! Yay!
ということで、1曲目は「from A to Z」をお送りいたしました！
And with that, our first song was "from A to Z"!
はい、この曲で今日は始めたいなと思って、今日は、えっとセットも演出も色々頑張って考えてきたのでよろしくお願いします。
Yes, I wanted to start today with this song, and I've put a lot of thought into the set and production, so I hope you enjoy it.
ということで、ま、5周年をAZKi迎えることができました！本当にみんなの応援のおかげで、ここまで、え、歩いて来れたと思っています。
That's right, AZKi was able to reach her 5th anniversary! I truly believe that thanks to everyone's support, I've been able to walk this far.
え、今日は、え、AZKi 5周年ライブということでこちらのハッシュタグでぜひぜひスクショや、え、ポスト、ポスト呟いてください。
Um, today is AZKi's 5th Anniversary Live, so please, please use this hashtag to share screenshots and posts!
ということで、今日はですね、事前に告知してありますが、え、お披露目、新衣装のお披露目あり、ゲストパートあり、最後に、お約束の告知と、さらに嬉しいお知らせもありということで、最後までお見逃しなく！そして
So, today, as announced beforehand, we have a new costume reveal, a guest part, some promised announcements, and even more happy news, so don't miss a second until the end! And...
早速ですがみんな気づきましたか？この後ろに！
But first, did everyone notice? Right behind me!
開拓者がいます！わー！開拓者！
There's a Pioneer! Wow, a Pioneer!
バーチャルの世界に3D化して現れてくれました！わー！わいわいわいわい！
It appeared materialized in 3D in the virtual world! Yay, yay, yay!
はい、ということで、開拓者とはですね、厳選でいっぱい戯れようと思っていますので、ぜひアンコールライブもよろしくお願いします！
Yes, so I plan to frolic plenty with the Pioneers, so please look forward to the encore live too!
ということで、えーと、えーと、そう、色んなことやんなきゃいけないから、え、水を飲みます。（笑）
So, um, um, right, I have to do various things, so I'm going to drink some water. (chuckles)
あ、水おいしい。ライブと言ったら水だよね。ということで、どんどん今日は盛り上がっていきたいと思います。その前にちょっと待ってね！
Ah, water is delicious. Water is a must at lives, right? So, I want to get more and more hyped today. But wait a second before that!
じゃん！こちらの猫耳をつけて、え、みんなと一緒に盛り上がっていきたいと思います！
Ta-da! Putting on these cat ears, I want to get hyped together with everyone!
ということで、次の曲はこの曲です。聞いてください。オメガ猫！
And with that, the next song is this one. Please listen to "Omega Neko"!
三食おひるね完備はあたりまえ！
Three meals and naptime included are a given!
（にゃん！にゃん！にゃん！にゃん！にゃんだふぉー！）
(nya! nya! nya! nya! nyandaho--!)
あとたまに褒め ナデデデも要望する！
And asking for occasional praise and head pats too!
そしたら十の愛をあげます 君にキュンとしてもらいます
Then I'll give you tenfold love, and have you swoon over me!
君とずっとしあわせを育てます
I'll cultivate happiness with you forever.
キュート盛り 吾輩こそ猫である！
Overflowing with cuteness, I am indeed a cat!
特別に君に触ることを許可する！
I specially grant you permission to touch me!
素直になれない本音のしっぽを
Chasing after my true feelings' tail,
追いかけて 優しくつかんでほしい
which I can't easily show, and catching it gently.
かまってくれなきゃ寂しいにゃ（にゃん！）
If you don't pamper me, I'll be lonely, nya (nyan!)
他のコ見てたらいけないにゃ（にゃん！）
You mustn't look at other girls, nya (nyan!)
ヒトのルールとか知らないにゃ（にゃん！）
I don't know anything about human rules, nya (nyan!)
ボクが一番カワイイにゃ！（にゃん！）
I am the cutest of all, nya! (nyan!)
にゃん！にゃん！君とずーっといたいので ボクに首輪をしといてね！（にゃんにゃん！）
Nya! Nya! Wanting to be with you forever, put a collar on me!
理解ってないね？そんなのなくたって ボクは君の運命の（にゃんにゃん！）
Understanding? Even without such things, I am your destined cat, nya!
にゃん！にゃん！夢がさめてしまうまで 鈴の鳴るたびかまってね！（にゃんにゃん！）
Nya! Nya! Until dreams awaken, every time the bell rings, stay with me!
君の愛のぜんぶをください
Please give me all of your love.
そしたら絶対絶対にゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぁー！
Then absolute-absolute nyanya-nyan! Nyan-da-fur!
にゃってかまって！にゃんにゃん！
Nyan, pay attention to me! Nya-nya-n!
アルファ・ベータ・ガンマ 変遷たどれば
Alpha, Beta, Gamma, if you trace the transitions,
とーぜん到達だ！目指すはオメガ
naturally we've arrived! Our goal is Omega.
君といきたいから果てまでラブ
Because I want to go with you to the ends of love,
だって、「ω」は猫マーク！！！！
after all, "ω" is a cat mark!
臆病で迷いがちな 小さなハートを
A cowardly, easily lost, small heart
受けとめて 両腕で包んでほしい
I want you to catch it and wrap it in both arms.
これでも愛情表現にゃん！（にゃん！）
Even this is an expression of love, nyan!
てかそれそろそろ気づいてにゃん！（にゃん！）
I mean, hurry up and notice already, nyan!
他人の言葉とか知らないにゃん！（にゃん！）
I don't care about other people's words, nyan!
ぼくが一番だいすきにゃん！（にゃん！）
I love you the most, nyan!
にゃん！にゃん！君とずーっといたので ボクに首輪をしといてね！（にゃん！にゃん！）
Nyan! Nyan! Put a collar on me since I want to be with you forever!
理解ってないね？そんなのなくたって
You don't get it? Even without something like that,
ボクは君の運命のにゃんにゃん！
I am your fateful nyan-nyan!
にゃん！にゃん！君に愛を尽くすから
Nyan! Nyan! I'll pour all my love into you,
ほかに浮気はしないでね？（にゃん！にゃん！）
so don't flirt with anyone else, okay?
理解ってしまった！触れた瞬間に
I understood! The very moment we touched,
君はボクの運命の！にゃん！にゃん！にゃん！夢がいつか叶うまで
you are my fateful nyan-nyan! Until our dream comes true,
猫の手を借りまくってね？（にゃん！にゃん！）
let's borrow cat paws as much as we can!
君の愛のぜんぶをください
Please give me all of your love.
そしたら絶対絶対にゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぁー！
Then absolute-absolute nyanya-nyan! Nyan-da-fur!
にゃってかまって！にゃんにゃん！
Nyan, pay attention to me! Nya-nya-n!
もっとかまって！にゃんにゃん！
Pay even more attention to me! Nya-nya-n!
もっと世界中で ただ優しい笑顔を見たいんだ
I want to see gentle smiles all over the world even more.
心まで響かせて
Let it echo deep into our hearts.
物語は何度だって続くよ
The story will continue no matter how many times.
ずっと もっと 歌っていたいよ
I want to keep singing on and on.
重なっていくほどに強くなるの
The more we overlap, the stronger we become.
一歩ずつ進んでく 旅路はまだ途中だよ
Moving forward step by step, our journey is still underway.
遠く離れていても 消えない未来があるんだ
Even if we're far apart, there's a future that won't fade.
少しずつ変わっても 繋がってく 奏でてくんだ
Even if we change little by little, we connect and play it on.
雨の日も晴れの日のも この想いが届くように
So that this feeling reaches you on rainy and sunny days alike.
見つけてあげるよ
I will find you.
想い出の数だけ描く フレーズは軌跡
The phrases drawn by our memories are our trajectory.
メロディは止まらないよ
The melody won't stop.
好きなんだ この場所でまた Ah Ah 笑顔のままで会いましょう
I love it, let's meet again in this place, Ah Ah, with a smile.
想像した以上に まだ伝えたいことがあるんだ
There's still more I want to convey than I ever imagined.
「ありがとう」じゃ足りない！
"Thank you" isn't enough!
ありふれた言葉だけど 聴いてて
It's a common phrase, but please listen.
探し続けていたんだ 心の奥を示すランドマーク
I've kept searching for the landmark that shows the depths of my heart.
きっと ずっと進んでく 旅路は夢じゃないんだ
I'm sure we'll keep moving forward, this journey isn't a dream.
鼓動早く鳴ような 愛してる景色があるんだ
There's a scenery of love that makes my pulse race faster.
少しずつ変わっても 繋がってる 奏でてるんだ
Even if we change little by little, we are connected and playing.
示した先にあるでしょ？ 私の想い届けたいな
It's at the end of what I pointed to, right? I want to deliver my feelings.
ここで会いましょう
Let's meet here.
想い出の数だけ描く フレーズは軌跡
The phrases drawn by our memories are our trajectory.
メロディは止まらないよ
The melody won't stop.
好きなんだ この場所でまた Ah Ah 笑顔のままで会いましょう
I love it, let's meet again in this place, Ah Ah, with a smile.
止め処なく溢れていく 真っ白な地図を見て
Looking at the pure white map overflowing endlessly,
少しずつ埋まってく 色とりどりの音楽
colorful music filling it up little by little.
雨の日も晴れの日のも この想いが届くように
So that this feeling reaches you on rainy and sunny days alike.
見つけてあげるよ
I'll find you.
はい、ということで、オメガ猫とフリージオをお届けしました！
Hi, so we brought you Omega Neko and FreGeo!
ちょっと張り切りすぎて、息が足りなかった
I got a bit too pumped up and ran out of breath...
けどまあ、ライブということで、はい。
But well, since it's a live show, yeah.
猫になれましたか、皆さん？ということで今日はね、
Did you guys become cats? So today, um,
こんな素敵なステージを作っていただきました。
you all helped create such a wonderful stage for me.
じゃあ、
Now then,
なんと地球儀が回っております。
the globe is actually spinning.
地球儀が回っていたり、えー先ほどは猫耳をつけたり、そして
The globe is spinning, and earlier we wore cat ears, and
これね地図のお姉さん帽子も付けてみたり、
we also tried wearing map-sister hats, and
色々とね演出をこだわってみましたが、いかがでしょうか？
we put a lot of thought into various productions, what do you think?
えーというわけで、AZKi 5周年を迎えまして、
So, welcoming AZKi's 5th anniversary,
本当に今年はですね、2023年は様々な天気がありました。
truly this year, 2023, had all sorts of weather.
えーね、2023年梅雨前線にハマって地図のお姉さんと成り
Um, 2023 got caught in the rainy season front and I became the map sister,
ましたけれども、誰がこんな、こんなことになることを予想していたでしょうか？
but who would have expected things to turn out like this?
そしてね、ありがたいことに、えー2023年10月4日にはビクターエンタテインメントからメジャーデビューもさせていただいて、
And thankfully, um, on October 4, 2023, I made my major debut from Victor Entertainment,
歌のお姉さんも頑張ってておりますよ。
and I'm doing my best as the singing sister too.
ということで、本当に、えー5周年を迎えられたことに感謝しております。
So, I truly am grateful to have reached my 5th anniversary.
1人では今日はここまで来ることができませんでした。
I couldn't have made it this far today all by myself.
開拓者のみんながAZKiを作ってくれたと思っています。
I believe all the pioneers created AZKi.
え、ビズユーはそんな意味も込めて、え、今日のライブタイトルにしました。
So 'BizYou' incorporates that meaning into today's live title.
はい、ということでですね、この後はみなさんお待ちかねのゲストパートに行きたいと思います！
So, after this, I'd like to move on to the guest part you've all been waiting for!
今日はですね、なんと、カナタンと坂又といろはちゃんが来てくれます！
Today, remarkably, Kanatan, Sakamata, and Iroha-chan are coming!
それでは行きましょう、頑張るぞ！えい！
So let's go, do your best! Yay!
君は誰とキスをする
Who are you going to kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl over there?
君は誰とキスをする
Who are you going to kiss?
星を巡るよ 純情
Wandering through the stars, pure emotion.
弱虫 泣き虫 連れて
Taking along a coward and a crybaby,
まだ行くんだと思う わたし
I think I'll keep going, that's what I feel.
愛する より 求める より
Rather than loving, rather than seeking,
疑う 方が ずっと はりやすい
Doubting is always much easier—
自己 が 悔しい 痛いよ
My ego is frustrating, it hurts.
味方 だけど 愛して ない とか
An ally, but not loving you,
守る けど 側 に 入れ ない とか
Protecting you, but unable to stay by your side—
苦い 二律背反
Bitter antinomy.
今 すぐ touch me
Right now, touch me.
運命 ならば つながせて
If it's fate, tie us together.
君は誰とキスをする
Who are you going to kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl over there?
こころ 揺する 言葉 より 無責任 に 抱い て 限界
Beyond words that shake the heart, holding me irresponsibly to the limit.
妄想 を 裁く オキテ
The code that judges illusion.
後ろ から 蹴り 上げ たら
If you kick up from behind,
むき出し の 恋 に よろけ た
I stumbled into raw love.
呼吸 だけ で 精一杯 迎 え に 来 て おぼれてる から
Breathing alone is all I can do, come meet me, I'm drowning.
痛い よ 前向き な 嘘 真に 受ける の は 笑ってる 声 ｾﾒﾅｲ から
It hurts. Believing a positive lie because the laughing voice doesn't blame me.
未来 も てあました
I've also wasted the future.
今 すぐ hold me
Right now, hold me.
理性 なんて 押し倒し て
Overpowering all reason.
君は誰とキスをする
Who are you going to kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl over there?
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl?
涙 まるで役立たず
Tears are totally useless,
星を巡るよ 純情
wandering the stars with pure emotion.
弱虫 泣き虫 連れて
Taking cowards and crybabies along,
What is this triangle for?
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl?
たったひとつ命をタテに いま振りかざす感傷
Risking my only life, waving my sentiment now!
はい、ということで、かなたん と、さかまた と、いっしょにトライアングラーを歌わせていただきましたー！
Yes, so together with Kanata and Sakamata, we got to sing "Triangler"!
ということで、かなけん 集合ー！
So, Kanaken assemble!
せーの、5周年 おめでとう！やったーー！
Ready, set, Happy 5th Anniversary! Yay!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
えーと、あずちゃん の、えー嫁の、天音かなた と、はい、えー、あずちゃんの、も、妻の、さかまたくろえ です。
Um, AZKi's, um, bride Amane Kanata, and yes, AZKi's, mo—wife, Sakamata Chloe.
いや、ちょっとざつ、めっっちゃ複雑な関係、複雑な関係というか、戸惑いながら、びっくりしてきちゃいましたけれども。
Man, it's such a complicated relationship... We were so bewildered and surprised by it all.
ふたりとも 今日は来てくれてありがとう！呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you both for coming today! Thanks for inviting us!
その時差は、かなけんで こう集合してライブがしたいなと思っていて、そう、今回一緒にライブができてとっても嬉しかったです、ありがとう！
Back then, Kanaken wanted to gather like this and do a live show, so I'm so happy we could finally do it together today, thank you!
こちらこそ、ありがとうございます、本当嬉しかった！
Same here, thank you so much, we're so happy!
いやなんかトライアングラー自体も、その三角キーをするものたちにみたいになってるしさかまたもね、3人で歌いたいなって思ってたしね。
Also, "Triangler" itself is about a triangle, and Sakamata also wanted us all three to sing it together.
いや、実わそう、なんかこう、なんかくさ、みんなでさ、こう選曲をね、どうしようかなって考えてる時に、さかまたもね、案をもらって、かなたにも意見をもらって、今回実現しました！やったー！
Actually, when we were thinking about song selection together, Sakamata and Kanata both gave their input, and we finally made it happen! Yay!
いや本当になんだかこう、1時間まるごとかなけんぐみみたいなのって、やっぱしてみたいよね、いつかさ。
Seriously, doing a whole hour just for Kanaken-gumi is something we'd love to try someday.
社長！いつかできますかね？やりましょうよ！
Boss! Can we do that someday? Let's do it!
やりましょうよ、僕たちも頑張って。それと、そうですよ、かなけんでね、オリジナル曲をね、いつか作りたいなって思ってますよ。
Let's do it, we'll do our best. And also, we'd love to create an original song for Kanaken someday.
え、じゃあまず、かなたはどんな曲を作りたいですか？
Oh, then first, Kanata, what kind of song would you want to make?
え、僕はね、やっぱこの3人だったら、ちょっと可愛い系の曲とかもいいのかなって思うんで、こう中毒性があって何度も聴きたくなるような、なんかピコピコ系の曲とか作ってみたいなあって思ってる。
Well, for these three, I think cute-sounding songs would be nice, like catchy, addictive electronic-pop style songs you'd want to listen to over and over.
おお、いいですねー！あいそう、2人にも。え、さかまたのは、あるの？
Oh, that sounds great! It suits you two. What about you, Sakamata?
えー、なんかそれぞれこう掛け合いとかのセリフがあるような曲だったらめっちゃいいな、ね！ピコピコともあいそう。それだ、わかりて、わかりて！
Um, something with dialogue or back-and-forth lines between us would be amazing! That would fit the upbeat style too. Totally get that!
いや、掛け合い最高だわ。いや、いいですねー、ということで、かなけんの音楽への熱い想いも聞けた、聞けた、聞けたところで、はい！
Back-and-forth lines are the best. So, we got to hear everyone's passionate thoughts on music, and with that—yes!
2人とはね、ここでとお別れとなりますー！やだやだやだー！
It's time to say goodbye to these two! No way, no way!
いや、今日はあずきの5周年ライブにかけつけてくれて、本当にかっこありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to celebrate AZKi's 5th anniversary live today!
ありがとうー！またねー！バイバーイ！バイバイバイバーイ！
Thank you! See you later! Bye-bye! Bye-bye-bye!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
An unmatched smile stirring up the media,
知りたいその秘密ミステリア
that secret, mysterious side you want to know.
抜けてるところさえ彼女のエリア
Even your clumsy side is part of your domain,
完璧で嘘つきな君は
you, perfect and full of lies,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius idol!
今日何食べた? 好きな本は?
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
Whenever you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない それは内緒
Haven't eaten anything, that's a secret.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Evading every question with a vague reply.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So cool and calm, yet brightly glowing,
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
secrets almost seen are as sweet as honey.
あれもないないない
There's none of that, that, that,
これもないないない
nor is there this, this, this.
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
What's your type? Who's your partner? Now answer me.
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
"I have no idea how it feels to love someone."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Whether it's true or false is impossible to know,
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
words like that make someone fall for you once again,
また好きにさせる
making them love you even more.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone gets captivated,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you are the perfect, ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
An existence that will never appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
the reincarnation of the brightest star.
その笑顔で愛してるで
With that smile, saying "I love you,"
誰もが目を虜にしていく
captivating everyone's eyes.
その瞳が その言葉が
Those eyes, those words—
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if lies, they are perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, that girl is special,
我々は端からおまけです
we're just extras from the start,
お星様の引き立て役Bです
just supporting actors B to the star.
全てがあの子のお陰な訳ない
It can't be thanks to her for everything.
史爛臭い 妬み嫉妬なんてない訳がない
There's no way there's no jealousy or envy,
これはネタじゃないだから許せない
this isn't a joke, so I can't forgive it.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
I can't forgive you if you're not perfect,
自分も許せない
I can't forgive myself either.
誰よりも強い 君以外は認めない
I won't accept anyone other than you, the strongest.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes and worships you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
truly the strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses to be found,
一番星を宿している
residing with the brightest star.
弱いところなんて見せちゃダメダメ
Showing any weakness is a big no-no.
知りたいところは見せずに
Without showing what they want to know,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
it has to be one and only, no way.
それこそ本物のアイ
That's true love right there.
得意の笑顔で濁すメディア
Clouding the media with your signature smile,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
only keeping this secret completely hidden.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
Building a career on the lie of "I love you,"
これこそ私なりの愛だ
this is my kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the flowing sweat is a clear aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
the eyelids hiding a ruby.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Dancing and singing, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the greatest love.
誰かに愛されたことも 誰かのこと愛したこともない
I've never been loved by anyone, nor have I ever loved anyone.
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること信じて
Believing that my lies will someday become the truth,
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
someday I'll surely get everything.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのことちゃんと愛したいから
Because I want to truly love everyone just as I am,
今日も嘘をつくの この言葉がいつか本当に なる日を願って
today I lie again, hoping these words will someday come true.
それでもまだ 君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, I couldn't say it to you and you alone.
ああ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない愛してる
This is definitely not a lie, I love you.
あずきちゃん5周年おめでとうございます!
Happy 5th anniversary, AZKi!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you!
ということでゲストにいろはちゃん来ていただきました!
And so we have Iroha-chan here as our guest!
イェーイお邪魔するでござる!
Yay, dropping in!
いやー今日は来てくれてありがとう!
Man, thank you for coming today!
イェーイイェーイ、こうやってまた一緒にね 歌って踊れて嬉しいでござるなあ!
So happy to sing and dance together again like this!
ねえ!
Right!
そう、いつもは風真の記念配信にね、来ていただくことが多いんですけども
Usually, you come to my anniversary streams, but...
今日はね、あずきの5周年にいろはちゃんをお呼びいたしました!
Today, I invited Iroha-chan for AZKi's 5th anniversary!
お邪魔しちゃいましたよ、呼んでいただけてすごーく嬉しいでござる!
I barged in, and I'm super happy to be invited!
いやもう、このあずきの5周年にはいろはちゃんがいないと…
I mean, AZKi's 5th anniversary wouldn't be complete without Iroha...
えっ?
Eh?
そんな、始まらないなんて…そんなへんに言っていただいてよろしいんですか?
You can just say it wouldn't start without me like that?
終わったあとにね、合わさせていただきました!
I matched up with you afterwards!
いや本当ありがとう!
No, really, thank you!
ということであずいろも今年は色々ありましたね!
So, Azuiro had a lot happen this year too!
本当に、なんか結構いたずら、一緒にね、長い時間で長い…長いよね。
Really, we've spent a long time together doing all sorts of things.
気づくするんだよね、ござるな。
It feels so long, indeed.
なんとですね、あずいろが結成したのは2022年9月17日ということで、あずいろ結成1周年経っておりました!
Believe it or not, Azuiro was formed on September 17, 2022, so it has already been 1 year since our formation!
え、そっか。そうか。
Oh, I see. Is that so?
そっか、あ、そんな日にね、そうだったよな。
Ah, right, on a day like that, yeah.
Androidガールを、あの、投稿した日よね。
The day we posted "Android Girl," right?
はい。結成日としまして、なんと1年が経っておりました。
Yes. As our formation anniversary, a whole year has passed.
あっという間！あっという間だね。
Time flies! It really flies.
なんか、でも今年はさらにね、いろんなまたさらに歌ってみたも出して、アイドルだして。
But this year, we released even more cover songs and debuted as idols.
アイドルだして、今日ね、このライブでね、一緒に歌いまして。
As idols, and today at this live, we sang together.
ね、もうかっこいいスクリーンにね、こちらね、キュートアイスクリーンにね、いただきました。
And we got to appear on such a cool, cute screen!
はい。映してもらって。
Yes. Featured on it.
で、今年は夏にいろいろ、あったな。
And this year, various things happened in the summer.
愛してるゲー、愛してるゲームとかもした、ような気がします。しますね。
We played games like the "I love you game," or something like that. We did, right?
そんな、あの、暑い夏をね、声優と一緒に食べて、暑い夏で。
Eating together in that hot summer, having a hot summer.
お買い物もしたし、食べたし、食べたしいろんなことしましたね。
We went shopping, ate delicious food, and did various things.
いろんなことした、え、今年2023年でございますね。
Various things happened this year, 2023.
本当に！いや、でもあっという間すぎて。
Truly! But time passed by so quickly.
でもこうやって5周年のにね、こうやって呼んでいただけると思っていなかったので。
But I never thought I'd be invited like this for our 5th anniversary.
とってもとっても嬉しくて、もう呼ばれた時からもう本当に。
I was so, so happy, ever since I got called.
嬉しい！で、これからもAZKiと色々ね、歌も踊りもやっていきたいな。
I'm so happy! And I want to keep singing and dancing with AZKi.
AZKiとやるってこと、こと、ことってことは、あります。AZKiよ。
Doing things with AZKi means... there are things. AZKi.
なんてね、今後ともよろしくお願いします！
Well then, we look forward to working with you!
あずき色、よろしくお願いします！イエーイ！ピースピース！
Azukiiro, nice to work with you! Yay! Peace, peace!
いや、すいませんね。あの、こちら関係者のよしみで聞いちゃったんですけど。
Ah, sorry about that. I happened to hear about it through connections, but...
なんか今回、新情報が、そう、あるとか、なんです？
Apparently there's new information this time, right? What is it?
なんと、AZKiこのあと新情報の発表をいたします！
We will announce new information about AZKi right after this!
え、いいんですか？いいんですか？
Eh, is that okay? Is it really okay?
みんなさ、見てて、くれる？
Everyone, will you watch it?
もちろんだよ！もう見てよカメラ、カメラ！
Of course! Look at the camera, camera!
カメラに向かって今日は、カメラに向かって、あ、もう可愛い、あ、可愛い！あ、なんて可愛いんだ！
To the camera today, towards the camera—ah, so cute! Ah, how cute!
このあとお披露目いたしますので、ぜひ最後まで見ていってね！
We'll have the unveiling right after this, so please watch until the very end!
いや、あ、でもそのために意気込みが必要でござるよな。
But for that, we need some enthusiasm!
そうなんです。あ、すいませんカメラさん。
That's right. Ah, sorry, camera person.
え、ちょっと、あの、今からですね、うちたあずき吉先輩のお披露目に参りますので。
We will soon go to the unveiling of senior Azuki-kichi, so please look forward to it!
あ、じゃあみんな少々お待ちいただいてよろしいですかね。
Everyone, please wait a moment.
はい、それでは着替えに行ってきます！先に行ってきますみんなもお楽しみに！
Alright, we'll go change clothes! See you later, everyone look forward to it!
行くぞ！おっきい、おっきい、おっきい！
Let's go! Big, big, big!
知らない言葉を 覚えていくたび
Every time I learn a new word,
おもかげのなか 手を伸ばすの
I reach out into my memories.
だけど一人では 分からない言葉も
But there are words I can't understand alone,
あるのかもしれない
perhaps.
さよならは苦くて
Goodbyes are bitter,
アイシテルは遠くにおいこした
and "I love you" was left far behind.
例えようのない この想いは
This indescribable feeling
とても怖くて だけどとても愛おしくて
is so terrifying, yet so dear.
わたし なんで泣いているんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて 答えたらいい?
What should I answer to my heart?
言葉はいつでも 語るでもなくて
Words are never simply for telling a story,
そこにあるばかり つのるばかり
they're just there, growing stronger and stronger.
わたしはあなたに 会いたくなる
I long to see you.
綺麗な言葉を 覚えていくたび
Every time I learn beautiful words,
自分のことが 嫌いになりそう
I almost start to hate myself.
だけど背を向けちゃ いけない言葉もあるのかもしれない
But there may be words I shouldn't turn my back on, too.
知らない言葉を 覚えていくたび
As I learn words I never knew before,
おもかげのなか 手を伸ばすの
I reach out into my memories,
だけど一人では 分からない言葉もあるのかもしれない
but there may be words I cannot understand alone.
さよならは 苦くて
Goodbyes are bitter,
アイシテルは 遠いにおいがした
and "I love you" had a distant scent.
例えようのない この想いは
This indescribable feeling
とても怖くて だけど
is so terrifying, yet
とても愛おしくて
so precious to me.
書きかけはやめた あて先のない手紙は
I stopped writing the letter with no destination,
風に揺れる 届けたい人の街まで
fluttering in the wind to the town of the one I want to reach.
始まりの 終わりを 伝えるために
To convey the end of the beginning,
生きること やめないこと
to keep living and never stop,
あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
so that I can be proud of today before you.
私なんで 泣いてるんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて 答えたらいい?
What should I answer to my heart?
言葉はいつでも 語るでもなくて
Words are never always meant to be spoken,
そこにあるばかり つのるばかり
they just exist there, growing ever stronger.
わたしは あなたに 会いたくなるよ
I find myself wanting to see you.
はい、ということで、皆さんお待たせいたしました！
Yes, so everyone, thank you for waiting!
新衣装 こちらになります！みんなどう？
Here is the new outfit! How does everyone like it?
と言うことで お届けした曲はTRUEさんの「Sincerely」でしたー！
So the song we just delivered was "Sincerely" by TRUE!
どうですか? えー 今回の新衣装のテーマをですね、コンサートドレスをテーマにお仕立ていただきましたー！
How is it? Um, for this new outfit, we had it tailored with a concert dress theme!
え、普段とは違った、豪華な装いとなってます。後ろもどうですか? どうですか?
Um, it's a gorgeous look different from usual. How's the back? How is it?
え、予想はみんなどうでしたか? あ、コメントたくさんありがとうございます！
Um, what did everyone expect? Ah, thank you so much for all the comments!
お、女神? え、本当に? 本当に?
Oh, a goddess? Eh, really? Really?
最高? あ、素晴らしい! 好き! 最高です、ありがとう!
The best? Ah, wonderful! I love it! It's the best, thank you!
みんな、どんな... じゃ、ここからはちょっとね、あの、スクショタイムということで、
Everyone, what kind of... Well, from here, it's a bit of a screenshot time,
あ、今回ね、場所を変えて、このラミーちゃんのね、ステージで、
Ah, this time we changed locations, and on Lamy-chan's stage,
今日ラミーちゃんお誕生日おめでとう! な、あの、運命の11月15日ということで、ちょっとラミーちゃんのステージをお借りして、えーと、おさせていただいておりますー!
Happy birthday today, Lamy-chan! As it happens to be the fateful November 15th, we borrowed Lamy-chan's stage to do this!
ということで、おきれ、おきれ、ありがとうございます! じゃあ、スクショタイムということで、
So, thank you very much! Well, as it's screenshot time,
あ、実はね、そう、ちょっと紹介が遅れましたが、マイクもこの衣装に合わせて作っていただいたんですよね、見てみて。
Ah, actually, yes, I was a bit late introducing it, but the microphone was also made to match this outfit, look.
こんな可愛いマイクになっておりますー!
It's turned into such a cute microphone!
いや、そう、あと、スタンドもね、可愛く綺麗に作っていただきましたー!
And also, the stand was made so cute and beautifully!
どんなポーズがいいですか? どんなポーズがいいですか?
What kind of pose is good? What kind of pose is good?
なんかね、今日のこのステージに合ってるね。
Somehow, it matches today's stage.
え、どうかな? でも、でもね、ドレスだから、あ、こんな、こんな、
Eh, how is it? But, you know, since it's a dress, ah, like this, like this,
どうですか? スクショタイム!
How is it? Screenshot time!
いっぱいスクショして、AZKi 5周年ライブでポストしてくださいね!
Take lots of screenshots and post them with the AZKi 5th Anniversary Live!
そして、マイクと、そう、実をこうね、こうティアラとかもね、こう作ってもらったり、
And the microphone, and the tiara was also made for me like this,
あとは、あとは、そう、サイドテールに...
And also, with the side tail...
髪型をしていただきまして、なんとね
Having my hair styled like this, you know,
ちゃんと、そう。色がインナーカラーが入ってるんですよ
and look, it has inner color, actually
なんとグラデーションで。可愛いでしょう？
in a gradation. Isn't it cute?
床になっとる。床になってますね、みんな。
Everyone is becoming the floor.
全方映がい...じゃくるりと。来る来ると。どうですか？
All-directional... wait, spinning around.
どうですか？可愛いですか？
How is it? Is it cute?
わーい。あ、みんな床になっとる、なっとる。
Yay! Ah, everyone's becoming the floor.
はい、というわけで、え、新衣装ね。
Yes, so, um, the new outfit.
えーと、ちょうどあの、去年の11月15日に新衣装を変更しまして、
Um, we changed to the new outfit
そこから1年が経ちまして、ま、こんなに素敵なね、本当歌を歌うのにぴったりな新衣装をね、お仕立ていただきました！
a year ago, and you made such a wonderful outfit perfect for singing!
床にならざるを得ない、ありがとう。
I can't help but become the floor, thank you.
ありがとうございます。今日は床が広い。確かに今日は床が広いね。
Thank you very much. Today the floor is wide.
いや、なのごとで、え、ぜひ新しいこんなあずきも、ぜひ好きになってくれたら嬉しいです！
Yeah, so I'd be happy if you'd come to like this new AZKi!
るんるん。私は床です。みんな床に、床になってる。
Run-run. I am the floor. Everyone's the floor.
あ、じゃあちょっと待って。次の曲に行く前にね、ちょっとお水を飲んでね、ここ湖だからね、お水はたっぷりありますということで。
Ah, wait. Before the next song, let's drink water—since this is a lake, we have plenty!
はい、水も飲んで。
Yes, drinking water.
それでは、ね、新たな衣装でですね、気持ちも新たに、えー、この衣装に合う曲を歌って行こうかなとなと思います。
Well then, in this new outfit with renewed feelings, I think I'll sing a song that matches.
はい、それでは次の曲、聞いてください。「藍深く」
Yes, well then, please listen to the next song, "Aifukaku".
藍深く
Aifukaku
目を閉じて
Closing my eyes,
耳を塞いで
stopping my ears,
やっと君を閉じ込めたのに
after I finally managed to trap you inside,
繰り返してる 呼吸に混ざって
mixing into my repeating breath,
少しずつ零れてしまいそうで
it feels like it's spilling out little by little,
いっそこのまま 誰にも届かない 深い夜の底で
so instead, in the depths of the deep night where no one can reach,
息を止めてしまいましょう
let's just stop breathing.
トクン トクンと 涙のかわりに
Thump, thump, instead of tears,
悲しくなるほど 音を立てる心臓
a heartbeat making a sound sad enough to break your heart.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know, I know it, but even so,
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
even now, I still love you so much, so terribly much...
口を噤んで 膝を抱えて
Shutting my mouth and hugging my knees,
そろそろ泣いてもいいですか？
can I finally start crying now?
繰り返す脈の 行き着く先まで
until the end of my repeating pulse,
私の全部に君がいた
you were in every part of me.
もう二度と君に触れられないこんな身体なら意味はなくて
if I have a body like this where I can never touch you again, it has no meaning,
もがいてもどうしようもなくて 酷く澱んだこの傷を掻きむしっている
struggling with nowhere to turn, I'm scratching at this terribly stagnant wound.
いっそこのまま 私にはいらない 暗い夜の後ろで息をしている
so instead, in the dark behind the night where I don't need it, I'm breathing.
明日なんて このまま泣いて全部零れたら
Tomorrow... if I just cry like this and let it all spill out,
君を知らない私になれるのかな
could I become someone who doesn't know you?
トクン トクンと 涙が枯れても この身体中を巡る焼けるような赤
Thump, thump, even if my tears dry up, a burning red circulates through my body.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど これじゃあまりにも この恋があまりにも
I know, I know it, but even so, this is too much... this love is too much...
これじゃあまりにも この恋があまりにも
This is simply too much, this love is simply too much...
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
Even now, I still love you this much, just this much...
息をしている 君は生きている
You are breathing, you are alive.
当然のことを誰も疑わないの
No one doubts something so obvious.
息をしているように見えている
It looks like you're breathing.
生の裏側 私にとっての何か
The flip side of life, what is it to me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping away.
叩かれても腐らずに此処で歌うよ
Even if I'm beaten down, I won't rot; I'll sing right here.
ボタン一つのいのち
A life hanging on a single button.
最後まで私のこと覚えていてくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの分かってよ分かってよね
It feels like I'm going to fade away, understand me, please understand.
本当のとこどうなの恋と推しは違うんでしょう
What's the truth? Are love and devotion different?
君が忘れちゃったら私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見ているよまたねバイバイ
I'm dreaming a dream like life, see you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, so I'm alive.
自己証明を欲しがって欲しがっているんだ
Desperately wanting proof of my existence.
音が止まって動かなくなって そんな私を君は笑ってくれるかな
When the sound stops and I stop moving, will you smile at someone like me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping away.
嫌われても腐らずに此処で歌うよ
Even if I'm loathed, I won't rot; I'll sing right here.
気分次第のいのち
A life governed by mood.
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれるの 覚めてしまいそうなの分かってよ分かってよね
Will you watch over me until the very end? It feels like I'm fading—understand me, please understand.
声が聞こえるんだよ 塩辛い涙が出ちゃうほど
I can hear a voice, enough to bring salty tears.
君が忘れちゃったら私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見ているよまたねバイバイ
I'm dreaming a dream like life, see you later, bye-bye.
ふさぎこんだあの日を軽くいじらないでやめて
Don't lightly poke fun at that gloomy day, please stop.
それが生きる糧になるから 大丈夫ずっと私は歌い続けるから
Because that becomes nourishment for living. It's okay, I will keep on singing forever.
最後まで私は生きているかわからないけど君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
I don't know if I'll be alive until the very end, but the words you gave me definitely remain.
最後まで私のこと覚えていてくれるの いつ死んでしまうんだろう分からない分からないよね
Will you remember me until the very end? I wonder when I'll die—I don't know, I really don't know.
最後まで私は生きているかわからないけど君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
I don't know if I'll be alive until the very end, but the words you gave me definitely remain.
最後まで私のこと覚えていてくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
いつ死んでしまうんだろう分からない分からないよね
I wonder when I'll die—I don't know, I really don't know.
痛いくらい気持ちがシンクロする時もあるけど
Sometimes our feelings synchronize so much it hurts, but...
君が忘れちゃったら私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見ているよまたねバイバイ
I'm dreaming a dream like life, see you later, bye-bye.
ありがとうございます！途中機材トラブルで
Thank you very much! There was some equipment trouble
音が飛んじゃいましたがこの後も聞いてね！
halfway and the sound cut out, but please keep listening after this!
はい、ということで、アリーナに戻ってきちゃいましたー！
Yes, so, I've come back to the arena!
どう、実はジャケットなしの、
You know, actually there's a new outfit version
新衣装バージョンもあるんです！どうでしょう？わー！というこで、
without a jacket too! What do you think? Yay! So...
ええ、お聞きいただいたのは「愛深くて命」でしたー！
um, what you just listened to was "Deep Love and Life"!
シンミリバラードパートは、いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like the sentimental ballad part?
ということで、ここでお待ちかねのあれを告知したいと思います！こちら！
So, I'd like to announce the long-awaited thing right here! Here it is!
AZKi活動5周年記念グッズ、発売しまーす！
AZKi 5th Anniversary merchandise is now on sale!
それでは内容を紹介していきたいと思います！まずアクリルパネル、こちら！
Now I'd like to introduce the contents! First, the acrylic panel, here!
イラストは、ビスケ先生に描いていただきました！自然の中で歌っているAZKiを、明るくて透明感のあるイメージで描いていただきました！新しい衣装のAZKiをぜひお家で飾ってください！
Illustrator Pisuke drew AZKi in nature, looking bright and transparent! Please decorate your room with this new outfit AZKi!
そして次、開拓者証明書！こちらもイラストはビスケ先生。あなたが開拓者であることを証明するカードになっております！シリアルナンバーと、裏面にはですね、AZKiのメッセージが入っています！
Next is the Pioneer Certificate card, featuring Pisuke's illustration proving you're a pioneer with a serial number and a message from AZKi on the back!
そして次、ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！こちらの可愛いミニキャラのイラストは、夢ノ内先生に描いていただきました！いろんな今回の新衣装と、普段の衣装の、バージョンが4パターンあります！こちらのAZKiのアクリルキーホルダー、飾ったりバッグにつけたりお出かけしてください！
Next is the Random Acrylic Keychain, with cute mini character illustrations by Yumenouchi! You can collect all four versions of her outfits and hang them on your bag!
そして次、開拓者ぬいぐるみ！開拓者3D化記念して、開拓者が、開拓者がついにぬいぐるみになりました！とっても可愛くできております！ホロライブフレーズのAZU友と一緒に並べたりして、楽しんでお出かけしてほしいなと思います！
Next is the Pioneer Plushie, turning the 3D Pioneer mascot into an adorable plushie that you can display alongside AZKi from hololive friends!
そして次、記念 voice！新しいこちらの衣装に合わせた内容のシチュエーションボイスとなっております！気持ちを込めて収録したのでぜひ聴いてください！
Next is the Anniversary Voice, a situation voice pack recorded with lots of love to match this new outfit, so please give it a listen!
そしてなんと、フルセットをご購入いただいたなら、こちら直筆サイン入りのポストカードを、なんと全員に書きます！AZKi頑張ります！メッセージは箱推しで届いてからのお楽しみです！そして特典ボイスもついてきます！5周年ありがたのメッセージ、感謝の気持ちを皆さんにお届けできればと思っています！開始はこのあと21時からですのでよろしくお願いします！
And if you purchase the full set, you'll get a postcard with a handwritten signature and a special voice message, plus a message shipped to you! Pre-orders open at 21:00 tonight!
そして、まだあります！嬉しいお知らせその2！こちら！LINEスタンプ、ホロライブ公式スタンプ「AZKi」が本日より発売開始いたします！
And there's more! The second happy announcement: the hololive official stamp "AZKi" is on sale starting today!
おはAZKiから親AZKiまで、普段使いしやすい全24種類、ぜひゲットしてたくさん使ってください！
From "Oh-AZKi" to "Parent-AZKi", 24 useful kinds for everyday use—please get them and use them a lot!
ということで、おしらせまだあります！こちらは告知のおさらいになります！SorAZメジャーデビューライブ「First Gravity」、2024年1月27日土曜日、クラブチッタにて開催いたします！こちらですね、現地チケットの二次先行が11月19日23時59分まで、そしてオフィシャルグッズもございます！11月26日23時59分まで発売となります！ライブ当日までにお届けいたしますので詳しくは概要欄をご覧ください！SorAZのリアルライブよろしくお願いします！
And one final notice: SorAZ Major Debut Live "First Gravity" will be held on January 27, 2024 at CLUB CITTA'! Check the description for ticket and goods details!
ということで、怒涛の告知でしたけれども、次の曲で最後になります！改めて5周年を迎えられたことに感謝しています！このルートにたどり着いたことは間違いじゃなかった！開拓者のみんなが連れてきてくれました！だから今日は最後にこの曲を届けます！この曲からAZKiは始まりました！今日この日をAZKiと一緒に過ごしてくれてありがとう！みんなと一緒にこれからも聞いてください！Creating World
Thank you so much for spending this special day with me, and I hope you'll continue listening to Creating World together with me!
この扉の向こうが未開の可能性なら
If the other side of this door is unexplored potential,
現実を動かすのか？
will it move reality?
暗闇を手探りで不安と焦燥の中
Groping through the darkness amidst anxiety and impatience,
こぼれる光を見た
I saw a spilling light.
手を伸ばしてこの未来はキミの物だから
Reach out, because this future is yours,
時間を超えて繋がるよココロが今
our hearts connect across time now!
創造するのだい私のストーリー
It's my story to create!
声を聞かせてキミを知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you.
生まれた意味を見つけるのさ 全てが始まるこの場所で
Finding the meaning of life, in this place where everything begins,
声が枯れるまで叫んで
I'll shout until my voice is hoarse.
言葉に傷つけられ悲しみが出こるのは
Getting hurt by words and feeling sadness
弱いからじゃないよ 勇気はあるから
isn't because you're weak—it's because you have courage.
掻き消されちゃ駄目なんだキミはキミのままでいい
You mustn't be drowned out; you can just be yourself.
声を上げて私達の歌は壊れない
Raise your voice, our song will never break!
何度だって伝えるよココロを今
I'll tell you however many times, our hearts resonate now—
共鳴するのだい私のストーリー
my story to create!
名前を呼んで側でいるから
Call my name, I'll be by your side.
音を奏でよう新しい世界 キミに出会う為に生きているんだ
Let's play music in a new world; I'm living just to meet you.
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle,
リアルを超えて繋ぐよ
we connect beyond reality.
私たちの歌は壊れない
Our song will never break.
何度だって伝えるよココロを今
I'll tell you however many times, our hearts resonate now—
共鳴するのだい私のストーリー
my story to create!
名前を呼んで側でいるから
Call my name, I'll be by your side.
音を奏でよう新しい世界
Let's play music in a new world.
キミに出会う為に生きているんだ
I'm living just to meet you.
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle,
リアルを超えて繋ぐよ
we connect beyond reality.
リアルを超えて
Beyond reality
繋ぐよさあ
we connect now!
夜は深く眠りに落ちて
Night falls into a deep sleep,
やがて光が世界を照らすよ
and soon light will illuminate the world.
キミと出会えたこと 意味を見つけたのさ
Meeting you, finding the meaning...
共に分かち合って生きていきたい
I want to live sharing with each other—
創造するのだい私のストーリー
my story to create!
声を聞かせてキミを知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you.
開拓するのだい新しい世界
It's a new world to pioneer!
嘘じゃないんだキミとのストーリー
It's no lie, my story with you.
全てが始まるこの場所で
In this place where everything begins,
歌を歌い続けるよ
I'll keep on singing songs.
今日は好き、5周年ライブ来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to my 5th anniversary live today!
6周年もよろしくお願いします！AZKiでした！
I look forward to year 6 as well! This was AZKi!
予告
[Teaser]
新企画
[New Project]
それは、AZKi本人の一言から始まった
It all started with a single remark from AZKi herself.
私、GeoGuessrが大好きなんですよ
I love GeoGuessr so much!
私、GeoGuessrを愛してるんです！！
I love GeoGuessr!!
GeoGuessrでGuessした場所にロケに行きたいんです
I want to go on location to places I guessed in GeoGuessr!
えっ！待って！
Wait, hold on!
えっ これ見たことある
Huh? I've seen this before.
わー！
Whoa!
頬張りすぎた…
I stuffed my cheeks too much...
AZKi 初めてのロケに行ってきました！
AZKi went on her very first location shoot!
お楽しみに！！
Stay tuned!!